# Jakob Troidl

Email: jakob.troidl@gmail.com Website: jakobtroidl.github.io GitHub: github.com/jakobtroidl

### ABOUT

I am a master's student in computer science at the Vienna University of Technology (TU Wien) who is deeply interested in data visualization, biomedical imaging, and computer graphics. My latest research focuses on applications of data visualization in neuroscience and climate sciences. When I am not prototyping new ideas, I enjoy rowing, reading philosophy, hiking, or just being in nature.

#### EDUCATION

TU Wien

Vienna, Austria

M.Sc. in Visual Computing, Advisor: Prof. Eduard Gröller

2019–Present

- Focus: Data Visualization, Biomedical Imaging, Computer Vision

- Current GPA: 1.0/1.0

TU Wien

Vienna, Austria

B.Sc. with Honors in Medical Informatics, GPA: 1.45/1.0

2015–2019

- Thesis: Flow Visualization on Curved Manifolds

- Among the top 5% of all computer science students

#### EXPERIENCE

#### Harvard University

Cambridge, MA 02/2020 - 08/2020

Research Fellow with Prof. Hanspeter Pfister  $\,$ 

,

- Scalable Comparison and Neighborhood Analysis of Nanoscale Brain Structures
- Development and design of a visual analysis tool to compare high resolution EM data

Brainlab AG

Munich, Germany

Research Intern

06/2019 - 08/2019

- Mixed Reality for 3D Medical Visualization
- Explored the potential of Mixed Reality in a clinical usecase

# King Abdullah University of Science & Technology (KAUST)

Thuwal, Saudi Arabia

02/2019 - 05/2019

Research Intern with Prof. Markus Hadwiger

- Observer Relative Flow Visualization in Curved Spaces
- Co-authored a publication which won the SciVis Best Paper Award at IEEE VIS 2020

Brainlab AG Munich, Germany

Research Intern

08/2018 - 01/2019

- Path Tracing for Realtime 3D Medical Visualization
- Worked on intraoperative navigation for neurosurgery

Jetsam GmbH Regensburg, Germany

Software Development Intern

08/2017 - 09/2017

- Developed a face recognition system for marketing purposes

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

[1] P. Rautek, M. Mlejnek, J. Beyer, J. Troidl, H. Pfister, T. Theußl, and M. Hadwiger, "Objective observer-relative flow visualization in curved spaces for unsteady 2d geophysical flows", *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics*, 2020.

# TEACHING

• Teaching Fellow at TU Wien	Fall 2020
Selected Chapters from Medical Visualization	
To a laborate Tollows of THE William	C

• Teaching Fellow at TU Wien Introduction to Visual Computing Spring 2017, Spring 2018

• Teaching Fellow at TU Wien
Introduction to Computer Engineering

Fall 2017

# SKILLS LANGUAGES

• Coding: C++, Python, Matlab, HTML, CSS, Java-Script, Java

English, German, Latin

• Tools: Unity, QT, CMake, Latex

# SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS

• Best SciVis Paper, IEEE VIS 2020 (among the best 3 papers out of 211 accepted papers)	2020
• Scholarship, Austrian Marshall Plan Foundation (9.100\$)	2020
- Bachelor with Honors, TU Wien (among the top $5\%$ of CS students at TU Wien)	2020
• Short-term grant for scientific work abroad, TU Wien (3.100\$)	2020
• Merit Based Scholarship, TU Wien (1.000\$)	2018

#### REFERENCES

- Eduard Gröller, Associate Professor, TU Wien groeller@cg.tuwien.ac.at
- Markus Hadwiger, Associate Professor, KAUST markus.hadwiger@kaust.edu.sa
- Johanna Beyer, Research Associate, Harvard University jbeyer@g.harvard.edu